Guide to the Henry P. Smith papers, 1966-1978?
Smith, Henry P. papers, 1966-1978?
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Henry P. Smith papers, 1966-1978?.
2867
Henry P., Smith 1911-.
122.1 cubic ft.
Includes transcripts of interviews, correspondence, requests for information, legislation, press clippings, voting records, inter-office memos, subject files, records of committees, and related records.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers of Henry P. Smith III from his terms as a United States Congressman from New York State.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Cornell University LL.B. 1936. ‡b Henry P. Smith III was born in North Tonawanda, New York on September 29, 1911. After he received a law degree from Cornell in 1936, he practiced law in Ithaca, New York until 1941, and then in North Tonawanda. He was elected mayor of North Tonawanda in November, 1961 and resigned in January, 1963 to accept appointment as Niagara County judge, surrogate and family court judge for one year. He was elected to the House of Representatives, serving from 1965 to 1974.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Papers of Henry P. Smith III from his terms as a United States Congressman from New York State. Includes transcripts of interviews, correspondence, requests for information, legislation, press clippings, voting records, inter-office memos, subject files, records of committees, and related records. Subjects include armed forces, crime, education, pollution, poverty, taxes, Vietnam War, agriculture, civil rights, drug abuse, and other issues.
ABBREVIATIONS USED
G 1
Agriculture
G 2
Air Force
G 2-1
Air Force requests
G 2-2
Niagara Falls 914th Tac
G 2-3
Air Force General
G 3
Army
G 3-1
Army requests
G 3-4
Corps of Engineers
G 3-5
Army miscellaneous
G 3-6
Nike sites
G 3-8
Selective Service (deferments, etc.)
G 3-9
Office of Civil Defense
G 4
Department of State
G 4-1
Immigration
G 4-2
Passports
G 4-3
General, Special Drug Project
G 4-4
World Academy
G 5
Department of Justice
G 5-1
Immigration and Naturalization
G 5-2
Justice Dept.--General
G 5-6
Federal Bureau of Investigation
G 6
Department of the Treasury
G 6-1
Internal Revenue
G 6-2
Customs
G 6-4
Treasury--General
G 7
Navy
G 7-1
Navy requests
G 7-3
Miscellaneous
G 8
Veterans Administration
G 8-5
VA--General
G 9
Post Office Department
G 9-5
Post Office--General
G 10
Civil Service
G 10-1
Positions
G 10-3
Civil Service--General
G 11
Miscellaneous
G 11-1
Positions
G 11-1.1
References, endorsements, etc.
G 11-2
Correspondence referred
G 11-3
Visitors
G 11-3.1
Group visitors
G 11-5
Speakers
G 11-6
Congratulations, greetings, thank you's, etc.
G 11-7
Page School
G 11-9
Flags
G 11-10
Maps and charts
G 11-11
Calendars
G 11-12
Tickets--football, baseball
G 11-13.1
Publications and information
G 11-13.2
Public laws, hearings, bills
G 11-13.3
Congressional Record
G 11-13.4
Congressional Directory
G 11-13.6
Farmer's Bulletins
G 11-13.8
Statements in Cong. Record
G 11-14
Misc. publications received
G 11-15.2
Press releases
G 11-15.3
Mailing list
G 11-17
Photographs
G 11-18
GPO
G 11-22
Crank
G 13
Invitations
G 13-1
Invitations accepted
G 13-2
Invitations declines
G 14
Political
G 14-1
Niagara County
G 14-2
Erie County
G 14-3
Conservative Party
G 15
Department of Health, Education, and Welfare
G 15-2
Social Security Administration
G 15-4
HEW miscellaneous
G 15-6
Office of Education
G 15-7
Food and Drug Administration
G 16
Federal Trade Commission
G 16-1
Federal Trade Commission
G 16-2
U.S. Tariff Commission
G 17
Department of Housing and Urban Development
G 17-1
HUD general
G 17-2
Housing assistance and renewal
G 17-3
Sewer and water projects
G 17-4
Section 235
G 17-5
Metropolitan Development Program
G 18
Civil Aeronautics Board
G 19
District projects
G 19-1
Olcott Harbor
G 19-2
SPUR
G 19-3
Erie and Niagara Counties Regional Planning Board
G 19-4
Floods on Ellicott Creek
G 19-5
Bull Creek
G 19-6
Times Beach
G 19-7
Tonawanda Creek
G 19-8
Deep Water Port on North Shore Niagara County
G 19-9
South Shore--Lake Ontario
G 19-10
Jetport
G 19-11
Niagara Falls International Airport
G 19-15
Bicentennial
G 19-17
High water levels--Lake Ontario
G 19-18
Eight Mile Creek
G 20
Department of Labor
G 21
Interstate Commerce Commission
G 22
General Services Administration
G 23
Department of Interior
G 24
Department of Commerce
G 24-1
Department of Commerce--general
G 24-2
Census Bureau
G 24-3
Patent Office
G 24-4
Procurement Fair
G 25
House Office Building
G 25-1
Office--Personnel
G 25-1.1
Mrs. I. Creaney
G 25-1
Mr. William B. Lewis
G 25-2
Mr. Philip A. Case
G 25-3
Disbursing Office
G 25-4
Parking Comm.
G 25-5
Clerk of the House
G 25-6
Stationery account
G 25-7
Telephone and telegram account
G 26
Department of Transportation
G 26-1
General
G 26-2
U.S. Coast Guard
G 26-3
Federal Aviation Administration
G 26-4
Federal Highway Administration
G 26-6
Railpax Amtrak
G 27
New York State
G 27-1
Bell Aerosystems Company
G 27-2
New York State Thruway
G 27-2
Buffalo Chamber of Commerce
G 27-3
General
G 27-4
Niagara Falls Chamber of Commerce
G 28
Atomic Energy Commission
G 33
Personal
G 34
Library of Congress
G 38
Federal Communications Commission
G 40
Department of Defense
G 40-1
DOD general
G42
Independent Offices and Establishments
G 42-1
SEC
G 42-2
Railroad Retirement Board
G 42-3
Federal Power Commission
G 42-4
Small Business Administration
G 42-5
National Labor Relations Board
G 42-6
National Aeronautics and Space Administration
G 42-7
Office of Economic Opportunity
G 42-8
General Accounting Office
G 42-9
EPA
G 42-10
ACTION
G 42-11
National Science Foundation
G 42-12
National Endowment for the Arts and Humanities
SUBJECTS
Names:
Smith, Henry P.,1911- .; United States.Congress.House.; United States.Congress--Officials and employees.
Subjects:
Agriculture.; Armed forces.; Civil rights.; Crime.; Education.; Pollution.; Poverty.; Taxation.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975.
Places:
United States--Armed forces.; United States--Politics and government.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Restricted to permission of the regional history archivist. Transcript of oral history interview with Smith conducted by Charles T. Morrissey requires permission of the Association of Former Members of Congress to quote or reproduce.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Code file (same as from Congressman William E. Miller)
Boxes 1-6
Series II. Alphabetical files
Boxes 7-9
Series III. Non-code chronological files
Boxes 10-11
Series IV. Other papers
Boxes 12-24
Series V. Papers received Jan. 12 and 23, 1973
Boxes 25-48
Series VI. Other papers
Boxes 49-123
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Code file (same as from Congressman William E. Miller)
  - G 1 to G 4-3 (Box 1)
  - G 5-1 to G 11-1.1 (Box 2)
  - G 11-2 to G 11-13 (Box 3)
  - G 11-13.1 to G 11-22 (Box 4)
  - G 15-2 to G 27-9 (Box 5)
  - G 28 to G 42-12 (Box 6)
- Series II. Alphabetical files
  - A-I (Box 7)
  - L-M (Box 8)
  - N-W (Box 9)
- Series III. Non-code chronological files
  - Jan.-June 1966 (Box 10)
  - July-Dec. 1966 (Box 11)
- Series IV. Other papers
  - Transcript of oral history interview with Smith conducted by Charles T. Morrissey (first session, June 7, 1978) for the Association of Former Members of Congress, 96 pp.; permission required to quote or reproduce (Box 12)
  - No box or code file list (Box 13-24)
- Series V. Papers received Jan. 12 and 23, 1973
  This is a preliminary listing of the papers received on the above date. The Code File has been put in numerical order (prior to the receipt of code file particulars from Naomi Glass, secretary to Congressman Smith) ca. 1967-1971, mainly 91st Congress, some 90th Congress.
  - Code file G 1 to G 3 (Box 25)
  - Code file G 3-1 (Box 26)
  - Code file G 3-1 (Box 27)
  - Code file G 3-4 to G 5-2 (Box 28)
  - Code file G 5-6 to G 7-1 (Box 29)
  - Code file G 7-3 to G 11-1 (Box 30)
  - Code file G 11-1.1 to G 11-13 (Box 31)
  - Code file G 11-13 to G 11-13.3 (Box 32)
  - Code file G 11-13.4 to G 15-4 (Box 33)
  - Code file G 14-4 to G 19-3 (Box 34)
  - Code file G 20 to G 25-6 (Box 35)
  - Code file G 26-6 G 38 (Box 36)
  - Code file G 40-1 to G 43-13 (Box 37)
  - ABM legislation (91st Congress) (Box 37)
  - Administration, Pro and Anti (Box 37)
  - Agriculture Committee (91st Congress) (Box 37)
  - Agricultural legislation (91st Congress) (Box 37)
  - Air pollution legislation (91st Congress) (Box 37)
  - Appropriations Committee (91st Congress) (Box 37)
  - Appropriations Committee--Medical research funds (91st Congress) (Box 37)
  - Armed Services Committee (91st Congress) (Box 37)
  - Balance of payments (empty folder) (Box 37)
  - Ballots (91st Congress) (Box 37)
  - 1976 Bicentennial Celebration (Box 37)
  - Cambodia (91st Congress) (Box 37)
  - Census legislation (91st Congress) (Box 37)
  - Chiropractic under Medicare legislation (91st Congress) (Box 37)
  - Civil rights legislation (91st Congress) (Box 37)
  - Congratulations, HPS. 1968. No. 1 (91st Congress) (Box 37)
  - Congratulations, HPS. 1968. No. 2 (91st Congress) (Box 37)
  - Conservative legislation (91st Congress) (Box 37)
  - Consumer affairs (Box 37)
  - Crime legislation (91st Congress) (Box 37)
  - District Day, Apr. 1970 (Box 37)
  - Drug abuse legislation (91st Congress) (Box 37)
  - Education legislation (91st Congress) (Box 38)
  - Education and Labor Committee (91st Congress) (Box 38)
  - Education (opposition to busing) (Box 38)
  - Electoral College legislation (Box 38)
  - End of Session Report, 1969 (Box 38)
  - Federal spending legislation (91st Congress) (Box 38)
  - Firearms legislation (91st Congress) (Box 38)
  - Foreign Affairs Committee (91st Congress) (Box 38)
  - Foreign aid legislation (91st Congress) (Box 38)
  - Government Operations Committee (91st Congress) (Box 38)
  - Health legislation (91st Congress) (Box 38)
  - HEW appropriations VETO (Box 38)
  - House Administration Committee (91st Congress) (Box 38)
  - Housing legislation (91st Congress) (Box 38)
  - Inauguration, Jan. 1969 (Box 38)
  - Interior and Insular Affairs (91st Congress) (Box 38)
  - Interstate and Foreign Commerce (91st Congress) (Box 38)
  - Labor legislation (91st Congress) (Box 38)
  - Medical legislation (91st Congress) (Box 38)
  - Medicare legislation (91st Congress) (Box 38)
  - Merchant Marine and Fisheries (91st Congress) (Box 38)
  - Middle East legislation (91st Congress) (Box 38)
  - Miscellaneous legislation, Proxmire Bill. S.3003 (Box 38)
  - Miscellaneous legislation (91st Congress) (Box 38)
  - National Endowment for the Arts (91st Congress) (Box 38)
  - National Guard Technicians, H.R.10249 and S.2031 (Box 38)
  - Oil imports file (Box 38)
  - Organization heads for 1970 (Box 38)
  - Pay raise legislation (Box 38)
  - Phosgene gas file (91st Congress) (Box 39)
  - Phosgene newspaper clips (Box 39)
  - Pollution (91st Congress) (Box 39)
  - Pollution--those who requested info. (Box 39)
  - Pollution--18-mile creek (91st Congress) (Box 39)
  - Pollution-general constituent letters (Box 39)
  - Pornography (91st Congress) (Box 39)
  - Post Office and Civil Service (Box 39)
  - Postal legislation (91st Congress) (Box 39)
  - Postal reform (Box 39)
  - Poverty legislation (91st Congress) (Box 39)
  - Powell, Adam Clayton (Box 39)
  - Public Works (91st Congress) (Box 39)
  - Pueblo legislation (Box 39)
  - Questionaire, 1969 (Box 39)
  - Questionaire, 1970 (Box 39)
  - Radio-TV (Box 39)
  - Railroad legislation (91st Congress) (Box 39)
  - Reordering priorities form (91st Congress) (Box 39)
  - Republican Campaign Committee (Box 39)
  - Republican National Committee (Box 39)
  - Republican Organization, House of Reps. (Box 39)
  - Rules (91st Congress) (Box 39)
  - Science and Astronautics (91st Congress) (Box 39)
  - Small Business Committee (91st Congress) (Box 39)
  - Social Security legislation (91st Congress) (Box 39)
  - Standards of Official Conduct (91st Congress) (Box 40)
  - Student disorders (91st Congress) (Box 40)
  - Tax legislation--single taxpayer (Box 40)
  - Single taxpayer petitions (91st Congress) (Box 40)
  - Tax legislation (from 1969 ) (91st Congress) (Box 40)
  - Tax legislation through Aug. 1969 (91st Congress) (Box 40)
  - Y.W.C.A. tax reform letter (tax-exempt org.) (91st Congress) (Box 40)
  - Pay T.V. (91st Congress) (Box 40)
  - Textile import letters, tariff legislation (2 folders) (91st Congress) (Box 40)
  - Trade legislation (91st Congress) (Box 40)
  - Un-American Activities (91st Congress) (Box 40)
  - Veterans Affairs (91st Congress) (Box 40)
  - Veterans legislation (91st Congress) (Box 40)
  - Vietnam legislation (91st Congress) (Box 40)
  - Vietnam Moritorium (91st Congress) (Box 40)
  - Voting age legislation (91st Congress) (Box 40)
  - Ways and Means (91st Congress) (Box 40)
  - Ways and Means Committee H.R. 3782 (91st Congress) (Box 40)
  - Welfare legislation (Box 40)
  - Welfare legislation thru Jan. 1971 (91st Congress) (Box 40)
  - Academies, 1969 (Box 41)
  - Air Force Academy, 1969 (Box 41)
  - Merchant Marine Academy, 1969 (Box 41)
  - Military Academy, 1969 (Box 41)
  - Naval Academy, 1969 (Box 41)
  - Betsch, Keith A., AF Academy, Class of '71 (Box 41)
  - Camann, Stephen P., AF Academy, Class of '72 (Box 41)
  - Neuland, Michael E., AF Academy, Class of '72 (Box 41)
  - Rajczak, William M., AF Academy, Class of '71 (Box 41)
  - Baxter, Richard B., Naval Academy, Class of '71 (Box 41)
  - Baldwin, Frederick A., West Point, Class of '71 (Box 41)
  - Benoit, John F., West Point, Class of '70 (Box 41)
  - Flood, John F., West Point, Class of '71 (Box 41)
  - Gustin, Maurice J., West Point, Class of '71 (Box 41)
  - Maday, Roy E., West Point, Class of '71 (Box 41)
  - McKeon, Thomas C., West Point, Class of '71, Presidential Appt. (Box 41)
  - Runge, Jerry D., West Point, Class of '71, Academy Appt. (Box 41)
  - Somers, Robert L., West Point, Class of '72 (Box 41)
  - Weber, Alfred J., Jr., West Point, Class of '72 (Box 41)
  - Buffalo Harbour, Black Rock Channel etc. Drift Resolution (88th Congress) (Box 41)
  - Bud Lesis (Box 41)
  - Phil Case (Box 41)
  - Iona Creaney (Box 41)
  - Pending cases plus misc. (Box 41)
  - Outgoing letters (copies), Jan.-Sept. 1967 (Box 42)
  - Outgoing letters (copies), Oct. 1967-July 1968 (Box 43)
  - Outgoing letters (copies), Aug.-Sept. 1968 (Box 44)
  - Outgoing letters (copies), Nov.-Dec. 1969 (Box 44)
  - Outgoing letters (copies), Jan.-Mar. 1970 (Box 44)
  - Outgoing letters (copies), Jan.-Oct. 1969 (Box 45)
  - Outgoing letters (copies), Apr.-Dec. 1970 (Box 46)
  - Outgoing letters (copies), Jan.-July 1971 (Box 47)
  - Outgoing letters (copies), Aug.-Dec. 1971 (Box 48)
  - Service Academy files for 1970; individual cadet files for 1973 graduates (Box 48)
- Series VI. Other papers
  - Bills introduced by Rep. Smith, 89th and 90th Congress (Box 49-50)
  - Judiciary Committee files, 89th and part of 90th Congress (Box 50)
  - Bills introduced by Rep. Smith, 91st and 92nd Congress (Box 51-53)
  - Judiciary Committee files, 92nd Congress (Box 54)
  - D.C. Committee files, 92nd and 91st Congress (Box 54-55)
  - Judiciary Committee files, 91st Congress (Box 55-56)
  - Speeches delivered by Rep. Smith, 1965-1971 (Box 57)
  - Miscellaneous photographs of Rep. Smith with others (Box 58)
  - Judiciary Committee, 89th Congress (Subcommittee #3) (Box 59)
  - Judiciary Committee, 90th Congress (Subcommittee #3 and 4) (Box 59)
  - Miscellaneous photos (Box 59)
  - Working files on End of Sessiion Reports and Questionaires (Box 60)
  - Background files, Water Pollution, Naigara Falls Remedial, Vietnam, Aid to Private Schools (Tax credit) (Box 60)
  - Legislative/Research Subject Files, 93rd Congress, A-E (Box 61)
  - Legislative/Research Subject Files, 93rd Congress, E-P (Box 62)
  - Legislative/Research Subject Files, 93rd Congress, P-Z (Box 63)
  - Voting records, 89th-93rd Congress (1st Session 93rd) (Box 64)
  - 91st Congress, Members of Congress for Peace Through Law (Box 65)
  - 92nd Congress, SPUR EDA Grant (Niagara Falls tourism) (Box 65)
  - 92nd Congress, Bell Aerospace Contract (Box 65)
  - 1967 World Peace Through Law Conference, Geneva (Box 65)
  - 1968 European trip, Judiciary Committee (Box 65)
  - 1971 World Peace Through Law Conference, Belgrade (Box 65)
  - 92nd Congress, Republican Task Force on Transportation (Box 65)
  - 92nd Congress Great Lakes Task Force (Box 65)
  - 1971 Ditchley Conference (Box 65)
  - 1969 Canadian Crude Oil problem (Ashland Oil) (Box 65)
  - Bills introduced by Rep. Smith in 93rd Congress (Box 66-68)
  - Files G 1 to G 3-1, 92nd Congress (Box 69)
  - Files G 3-1 to G 4-2, 92nd Congress (Box 70)
  - Files G 4-3 to G 7-1, 92nd Congress (Box 71)
  - Files G 7-1 to G 11-1, 92nd Congress (Box 72)
  - Files G 11-1 to G 11-13, 92nd Congress (Box 73)
  - Files G 11-13 to G 11-13.2, 92nd Congress (Box 74)
  - Files G 11-13.3 to G 15-2, 92nd Congress (Box 75)
  - Files G 15-4 to G 20, 92nd Congress (Box 76)
  - Files G 21 to G 26-4, 92nd Congress (Box 77)
  - Files G 26-5 to G 42-9, 92nd Congress (Box 78)
  - Service academies, 1971-1972 (Box 79)
  - Service academies, 1973-1974 (Box 80)
  - Chronological files, Nov. 1972-June 1973 (Box 81)
  - Chronological files, Jan.-Feb. 1974, July-Dec. 1973 (Box 82)
  - Chronological files, Mar.-Oct. 1974 (Box 83)
  - Chronological files, Jan.-Oct. 1972 (Box 84)
  - Press releases, 91st-92nd Congress (Box 85)
  - G 42-9, 92nd Congress (Box 86)
  - Subject files (legislative), A-P, 92nd Congress (Box 86)
  - 92nd Congress, subject files, P-V (Box 87)
  - 92nd Congress, subject files, W-Z (Box 88)
  - Committee files (except Judiciary and D.C.) (Box 88)
  - Campaign files, 1964-1972 (Box 89)
  - Military, VA, and Social Security case files (Box 90-91)
  - G 1-Agric., G 2-Air Force, G 3 thru 1973 -Army (Box 92)
  - G 3 thru 1974 -Army, G 4-Dept. of State (Box 93)
  - G 5-Justice, G 6-Treasury, G 7-Navy (Box 94)
  - G 8-5-Veterans' Administration, G 10-Civil Service, G 11-1-Positions (Box 95)
  - G 11-1.1-Recommendations thru G 11-9-Flags ( 1973 ) (Box 96)
  - G 11-9 Flags ( 1974 ) thru G 11-13 (Box 97)
  - G 11-13.1 thru G 11-22 (except G 11-17) (Box 98)
  - G 11-17, G 14, G 15-2 thru Dec. 1974 (Box 99)
  - G 15-2 (cases) thru G 16 (Box 100)
  - G 17 thru G 19-10 ( Dec. 1972 ) (Box 101)
  - G 19-10 thru G 19-22 (Box 102)
  - G 20 thru G 24-3 (Box 103)
  - G 26-1 thru G 40 (Box 104)
  - G 42 thru G 42-12, G 9-5, individual Post Office files (Box 105)
  - Subject A-H (Box 106)
  - Subject I-P (Box 107)
  - Subject Q-Z (Box 108)
  - Committees--Agriculture, Appropriations, Atomic Energy Commission, Armed Services, Banking and Currency, Education and Labor, Foreign Affairs, Government Operations, House Administration, Interior and Insular Affairs, Internal Security, Interstate & Foreign Commerce, Merchant Marine & Fisheries, Post Office & Civil Service, Public Works, Rules, Science & Astronautics, Veterans' Affairs (Box 109)
  - Ways and Means Committee; miscellaneous--Niagara Falls Remedial Works; G 21-Rail Reorganization (Box 110)
  - 93rd Congress press releases (Box 111)
  - 1972-1973 press releases, 1973-1974 speeches; 1975 Service Academy files (Box 112)
  - Judiciary Committee; District of Columbia Committee (Box 113)
  - Judiciary Committee cont'd, patent reform legislation (Box 114)
  - Projects (Niagara Falls Sewage Treatment Plant, 1972-1973; All American Canal; Niagara County Redevelopment Area Designation; Model City AEC Proposal, 1965-1966; Tonawanda Island Bridge, 1965-1966; North Tonawanda Refuse Disposal Machine; Wilson Harbor Dredging Project; Urban Planning Assistance Grants, 1967-1968 ) (Box 115)
  - Rockefeller Confirmation material (Judiciary) (Box 116-117)
  - Loose-leaf binders of press clippings and Smith's official voting record for 92nd and 93rd Congresses (Box 118-119)
  - Scrapbook, 1969-1971; copies of correspondence, 1966-1974; inter-office memos from Washington, D.C., 1966-1974 (Box 120)
  - Inter-office memos to Washington, D.C., 1966-1974; coded subject files, G 0 to G 9 (Box 121)
  - Coded subject files, G 10 to G 15 (Box 122)
  - Coded subject files, G 17 to G 42; Subject files, 1965-1974; Corps of Engineers, 1966-1973 (Box 123)